when a court Awards a mortgage holder
damages for waste the property owner
appeals and the court lays waste to the
owner in Prudential Insurance versus
Spencer's Kenosha ball
Co development owned a building
Prudential held a mortgage on the
building Delco sold the building to
Spencers but Spencer's didn't take over
the mortgage Delco defaulted on the
mortgage because the building secured
the mortgage Prudential foreclosed on it
even though it belonged to Spencer's
Prudential tried to recover the money
owed through a sheriff's seal of the
building the building sold for 635
thousand dollars then over three hundred
thousand dollars remained on the
mortgage which was the debt deficiency
while Spencer's owned the building it
fell into disrepair including the
development of problems with the roof
Spencer's also owed property taxes
Prudential claimed that Spencer's
committed waste because of the condition
of the property
at a hearing the judge found for
Prudential the sum of the building's
damages and outstanding property taxes
was higher than the debt deficiency so
the judge ordered Spencers to pay the
deficiency and a small amount for rent
Spencer's appealed the courts award for
Waste to the Wisconsin Court of Appeals